# Himanshu Suman

### Senior Software Engineer

IT Professional with 5.5 years of experience in analysis, design, development, testing and implementation of various applications. Experienced in Agile Methodology as well as good understanding of all the phases of Software Development Life-Cycle(SDLC). Exposure to Banking, US Healthcare and Insurance domain. Experience in technologies like JAVA, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Angular, Apache Camel, SOAP and REST, JBPM, ActiveMQ, Amazon SQS and relational databases like MySQL and Oracle.



himanshu.gvu@gmail.com



+65 97919091



Singapore

in

linkedin.com/in/himanshusuman



himanshusuman1

#### **SKILLS**

Core Java, J2EE

Spring Boot, Spring MVC, Angular, Hibernate

Apache Camel

**JBPM** 

ActiveMQ, Amazon SQS

Quartz Schedular

MySQL, Oracle

Docker, Kubernetes

Apache Tomcat, WebLogic, JBoss

Maven, Jira, Github, Jenkins

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Application Lead Developer Citibank

10/2018 - Present

Role and Responsibility

- Worked on the Citi AML project for risk calculation engine.
- Technologies used were JAVA, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Oracle, JBPM

### Senior Software Engineer

#### Mscripts

04/2016 - 09/2018

Role and Responsibility

- Involved as developer in the product development, maintenance and to configure the plain vanilla product as per the requirement from various pharmacy clients.
- Developed Camel routes, configured Camel with ActiveMQ. Developed end to end process flow using JBPM for the Pharmacy solutions.
- Technologies used were JAVA, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Angular, Apache Camel, ActiveMQ, Docker, JBPM, Amazon SOS.

#### **Programmer Analyst**

#### Cognizant Technology Solutions

01/2014 - 04/2016

Role and Responsibility

- Worked on the portal for Capital One bank that enables the Bank's Call Centre or Branch executives to manage the service requests or complaints of the customers pertaining to their various bank products. Technologies used were JAVA, Spring, Hibernate, JBPM, Drools and MySQL.
- Worked on the Retirement income planner project for TIAA-CREF which creates hypothetical scenarios showing how much income you might expect post-retirement. Technologies used were JAVA, Spring, SOAP service, Oracle.

#### **AWARDS AND ACCOLADES**

Secured 2nd Place in Futurize Hackathon organized by Mscripts

Pat on the Back 2016

#### INTERPERSONAL

Good Team Player

Adaptable in any Environment

Good at Public Speaking

Ad-hoc Scrum Master

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering**

Gyan Vihar School of Eng. and Tech.

06/2009 - 07/2013

#### LANGUAGE KNOWN

English, Hindi